<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/</link><description>Recent content on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Kevin Klein</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 07:38:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevinkle.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Celeriac strawberry salad</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-24-celeriac_strawberry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-24-celeriac_strawberry/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 large celeriac 250g of strawberries 100g hazelnuts 1 handful of radishes 1 large bunch of basil 3 tablespoons of tahini 3 large tablespoons of greek yoghurt 1 tablespoon of sweet paprika powder Method After trimming off the skin of the celeriac, grate thin strips of it. Sauté these in some olive oil, occasionally deglazing them with balsamic vinegar.
Cut the hazelnuts in half and toast them in a dry pan until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Mantras</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-05-mantras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-05-mantras/</guid><description>A system just can&amp;rsquo;t respond to short-term changes when it has long-term delays. Donella H. Meadows, Thinking in Systems Always be closing. Am meisten erreicht man, wann man den Lustgewinn aus den Quellen psyschicher und intellektueller Arbeit genügend zu erhöhen versteht. Sigmund Freud, Das Unbehagen in der Kultur Be a parent to yourself. A wise Hacker News user Defend those who are absent. Steven Covey, 7 Habbits of Highly Effective People Don&amp;rsquo;t confuse effort with result.</description></item><item><title>Conspicuous Kohlrabi</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-07-04-kolhrabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-07-04-kolhrabi/</guid><description>Ingredients Serves two for a rather light or one for a truly lavish lunch.
1 large kohlrabi 100g baby spinach 8 radishes 200g greek yoghurt 100g blueberries 100g hazelnuts 4 tablespoons tahini half a bunch of parsley half a bunch of mint 1 heaped teaspoon of cumin 1 heaped teaspoon of smoked sweet paprika 1 teaspoon of sumac 1 teaspoon of coarse mustard black sesame seeds juice of 1 lemon Method Trim off the kohlrabi&amp;rsquo;s peel and grate it to thin strips/slices with some kind of a grater.</description></item><item><title>Observations About My Gym</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-25-gym/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-25-gym/</guid><description>The gym operators have three folders in their open office, one of which is titled &amp;lsquo;problems&amp;rsquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;m gently reminded that I haven&amp;rsquo;t leetcoded in a long while and that the days taking classes on algorithms and data structures have long been gone while trying to find a pair of matching dumbbells of a specific weight.
A guy once seriously protested that he cannot possibly not be topless while training.
You have to pay extra to take a shower.</description></item><item><title>Who With Whom, What With What</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-21-friends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-21-friends/</guid><description>The following is an illustration of a graph optimization problem. I chose to instantiate it with a decision making process revolving around a social setting. Yet I hope its general applicability comes across.
Setup Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have the opportunity to invite people to an event. The pool of candidates is comprised of five people: Tony, Paulie, Silvio, Furio and Vito. What we care about is for the attendants to have a good time - which we assume to be purely determined by who else is attending.</description></item><item><title>Inference</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-06-inference/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-06-inference/</guid><description>I had long felt a slight discomfort with the word &amp;lsquo;inference&amp;rsquo;. Many people seemed to use it with confidence and the expectation that it would refer to a precise notion. And while it is not uncommon for a word to have different meaning in different contexts, it took me a while to figure out what the different meaning and what the different contexts are in the example of &amp;lsquo;inference&amp;rsquo;. Some other people seem to be a little confused as well.</description></item><item><title>Life Monitor</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-21-life_monitor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-21-life_monitor/</guid><description>Motivation On the one hand, there are things we notice &amp;lsquo;automatically&amp;rsquo;, easily, without consciously paying attention to them. On the other hand, there are things that slip through the cracks unless we make a point out of monitoring them.
It might seem very natural that whether something is effortlessly &amp;lsquo;visible&amp;rsquo; is highly dependent on other properties of that very same something. It occurred to me that I have a tendency to be less receptive for observations that</description></item><item><title>PB Granola</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-20-pb_granola/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-20-pb_granola/</guid><description>Ingredients 300g of rolled oats 100g of dark chocolate 100g of pecan nuts 50g of Brazil nuts 3 massively heaped tablespoons of crunchy peanut butter 2 massively heaped tablespoons of coconut oil 3 tablespoons of honey (preferably runny) 2 tablespoons of cocoa powder 1 tablespoon of vanilla sugar 1 tablespoon of cinnamon a dash of salt Method Roughly chop the nuts and finely chop the chocolate. Mix all together, making sure the coconut oil melts in the process of doing so.</description></item><item><title>Org Log</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-27-org_journal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-27-org_journal/</guid><description>I have long been an avid enthusiast of journaling. This has mostly been for the sheer sake of journaling. In other words: once written, never to be read.
At the same time I would like to use information about my past when making decisions for the future. When simply winging this inference on empirical data, I&amp;rsquo;m always worried that some warping could have altered my recollection of these experiences (in other words: a noisy communication channel) and thereby bias my inference mechanism unjustly.</description></item><item><title>Goals Are Arbitrary</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-18-goals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-18-goals/</guid><description>I have the pleasure of having impressive friends who have completed and continue to complete spectacular athletic feats. Some crossed the alps with a single speed steel tandem bike. Some run 10k in 35&amp;rsquo;. Some run half-marathons with more than 2000m of elevation literally called inferno. And then, of course, there is the camp of people who go about this whole ironman business.
Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a difficult relation to &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sudoku #3: Poor Man's RL</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-09-sudoku_rl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-09-sudoku_rl/</guid><description>Previously, I&amp;rsquo;ve outlined some ideas on how to solve Suduko puzzles. One revolved around depth-first search in trees, one around linear programming. This time I tried my luck with a more adventurous, data-driven approach: Reinforcement Learning. First things first: the approach only works well for 4x4 grids - not for the typical 9x9. Please note that the approached subsequently outlined couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from a recommendable approach to solving Sudoku puzzles.</description></item><item><title>Fig Appetizers</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-01-fig_appetizers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-01-fig_appetizers/</guid><description>Quick to make, satisfying to eat.
Ingredients Puff pastry Figs (preferably fresh ones; if not, dried ones are ok, too) Ricotta Rocket Method Cut some parts of the puff pastry. I figure both rectangles and squares should work. While all sizes &amp;lsquo;go&amp;rsquo;, I think that in principle one wants to use as little dough per fixed filling size as possible. In the same vein, I would try to make the pastry as thin as possible.</description></item><item><title>2021 in Consuming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-28-2021_consuming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-28-2021_consuming/</guid><description>Just rambling about some books, music and podcasts I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to in 2021. I did a similar thing in 2020.
Books A Supposedly Fun Thing I&amp;rsquo;ll Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments - David Foster Wallace I much preferred the short story about the dynamics of professional tennis over DFW&amp;rsquo;s hesitant adventures on the high seas after which the book is titled. The distinguishing quality might have been positivity. While tries to convey a lot of criticism and scepticism towards tennis, yet can&amp;rsquo;t help but let raw rays of juvenile sunshine through his cover of rationality.</description></item><item><title>2021 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-27-2021_running/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 02:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-27-2021_running/</guid><description>As another year is coming to an end I&amp;rsquo;m curious: What has my running looked like this year? I did something similar in 2020 as well as in 2019.
The gist of it 2018 2019 2020 2021 distance [km] 430 962 1295 1381 avg distance [km] 6.61 9.08 10.53 11.05 #runs 65 107 123 124 #sports activities 81 135 210 231 share of running among sports activities 80.25% 79.26% 58.57% 53.</description></item><item><title>Automn Pie</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-10-17-pie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 10:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-10-17-pie/</guid><description>This is a really hearty dish. I&amp;rsquo;d claim that the filling of the pie can easily be prepared in advance.
Core ingredients Serves 4 okay-ish hungry people.
1kg smoked tofu 1kg green beans 500 ml coconut milk ~500g shortcrust dough 2 cans of chickpeas 3 carrots 3 large yellow onions 3 gloves of garlic half a thumb of ginger small chili soy sauce black bean sauce tomato purée soy sauce red wine 1 egg Method Strain your chickpeas and separate them out on a baking tray.</description></item><item><title>Flaky Tofu</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-09-25-flaky-tofu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 10:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-09-25-flaky-tofu/</guid><description>Ingredients Serves 3 hungry fellows.
Tofu 1kg firm tofu 200 mL unsweeetened soy milk 100 g flour 3 tablespoons[0] corn starch 200g unsweetened corn flakes Dipping sauce 4 tablespoons peanut paste 4 tablespoons black bean sauce (see below for an image) 4 tablespoons tomato purée 2 tablespoons of rice wine vinegar dash of soy sauce soymilk corn starch Salad ~500g carrots 2 large cucumbers sesame oil soy sauce rice wine vinegar Method Get ahold of two shallow dishes for the batter.</description></item><item><title>Sudoku #2: Linear Programming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-03-14-sudoku_lp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 11:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-03-14-sudoku_lp/</guid><description>Abstract As discussed in this previous post, a given Sudoku puzzle can be modeled in a multitude of ways. Different algorithms ought to still lead to the same solution, since a correct Sudoku puzzle comes with a unique solution. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll rely on optimization&amp;rsquo;s poster child: Linear programming.
Idea A linear program, subsequently referred to as LP, comes with three central building blocks:
An objective function Typically many variables, each, a priori, non-integer numbers Linear constraints on the variables Since, thanks to our assumption of a well-posed puzzle we know that:</description></item><item><title>Sudoku #1: Depth-First Search</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-02-28-sudoku_dfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 19:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-02-28-sudoku_dfs/</guid><description>Abstract Solving a Sudoku board can be done in many ways. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore a depth-first search approach in this post.
Idea Depth-first search or DFS implies (at least) two things:
a graph, or rather, a tree a search This bares the question: What&amp;rsquo;s the tree and what are we searching for?
The tree A tree must consist of nodes and edges. We define the nodes to represent a &amp;lsquo;state&amp;rsquo; of the game.</description></item><item><title>Expectations are Twofold</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-17-expecations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-17-expecations/</guid><description>I caught myself making the mistake of thinking I wasn&amp;rsquo;t holding expectations when in fact, I was.
When telling myself to not have a certain expectation against someone, I did usually make sure to control my behaviour towards them. If I anticipated that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the expectation of an event taking place, I made sure not to make the responsible person feel negatively about the non-event. I figured that not holding the expectation would mean that I may not act upset or angry towards them.</description></item><item><title>I Could Care Less</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-13-caring/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 18:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-13-caring/</guid><description>While I think that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing okay when it comes to not caring too much about other people&amp;rsquo;s perception of me, I believe to have spotted some weak spots recently.
I think there is still a distinction to be made when it comes to &amp;lsquo;caring&amp;rsquo;. I feel like there is a qualitative difference between caring about what exactly others think of me when in their presence and caring about an imagine I have of myself - hypothetically representing me towards others - but practically never witnessed by anyone.</description></item><item><title>2020 in Consuming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-02-2020_consuming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-02-2020_consuming/</guid><description>Just rambling about some books, podcasts and records I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to a bunch over 2020.
Books How to Solve It - George Pólya Classical asymmetry: obvious once you see it.
Slaughterhouse Five - Kurt Vonnegut I think I&amp;rsquo;ll remember the poor soul claiming to have lived through much worse until he didn&amp;rsquo;t.
Consider the Lobster - David Foster Wallace This was when I realized how bad at languages I am.</description></item><item><title>2020 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-12-27-2020_running/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-12-27-2020_running/</guid><description>Yet another year&amp;rsquo;s almost over. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at my year 2020 in running, just as I did in 2019.
Yearly comparison 2018 2019 2020 distance [km] 430 962 1295 avg distance [km] 6.61 9.08 10.53 number of runs 65 107 123 share of running among sport activities 80.25% 79.26% 58.57% I picked up going to the gym in late 2019 and started cycling every now and then in 2020, hence the lower share of running.</description></item><item><title>The Value of the Past</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-25-value-of-past/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 15:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-25-value-of-past/</guid><description>When looking into the future, the definition of ambitions is often intertwined with an assessment of their feasibility. There are two, frequently opposing, guiding principles at work:
Be who, how and what you want to be. The past tells you what works for you and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t. The former being a fairly idealistic and empowering maxim, possibly reminiscent of rationalism, I like to think of the latter as Realpolitik on a personal level with a scent of empiricism.</description></item><item><title>On Working Fast</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-24-working-fast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-24-working-fast/</guid><description>Many discussions regarding software tooling had me facing the argument that while my suggestions might decrease the duration required for the task at hand to some degree, the magnitude or quantity of the savings were not sufficiently significant, that they would not amortize. Despite acknowledging a taste of truth to that, I typically felt that there was an aspect to the topic escaping the debate.
The relevance of speed in workflows always carried conviction to me.</description></item><item><title>On Gifts</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-08-03-gifts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 15:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-08-03-gifts/</guid><description>TL;DR: Spend thought not money. Think about your edge. Don&amp;rsquo;t buy beans for a hobby roaster.
I&amp;rsquo;ve often felt strongly about gifts made and received and always had some vague intuitions floating around in my head concerning distinctive properties. Finally have I sought to distill them and make them more explicit.
Reflecting on past gift-finding processes, I came to realize that I would often feel dissatisfied when most of the value of a gift would stem from money.</description></item><item><title>Fig Quiche</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-07-25-fig_quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-07-25-fig_quiche/</guid><description>Ingredients 300g shortcrust dough large bunch of basil ~200g Soft, creamy goat cheese, e.g. Chavroux ~400g of figs (both fresh and dried are ok) 4-6 red onions 2 cloves of garlic zest of one lemon ~3 eggs ~80ml cream [0] some lemon juice some nutmeg some sweet paprika powder seasoning Method Slice the red onions in rings and fry them under medium-high heat with both olive oil and butter. Consider adding more oil to get to where you want to be.</description></item><item><title>Orange Pink Eggs</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-16-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 21:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-16-eggs/</guid><description>I have a feeling that hard-boiled eggs are conventially viewed as unsexy. In spite of that, I gave pickling them a shot.
Ingredients 8 eggs 1 cup of white balsamic vinegar 1/2 cup of liquid from tinned beets 2 tbsp cardamon pods 2 tbsp cumin seeds 2 tbsp coriander seeds 2 tbsp pepper corns 1 tbsp fennel seeds 1 tbsp mustard seeds a few cloves a few bay leaves 2 cloves of garlic 2 tbsp curry powder 2 tbsp turmeric 2 tbsp sweet paprika powder 2 tbsp salt 3 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp garam masala Method Boil the eggs as little as possible while making sure they&amp;rsquo;re actually boiled.</description></item><item><title>Caramelized Onion and Artichoke Ravioli</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-25-ravioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 15:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-25-ravioli/</guid><description>Ingredients Dough
300g of 00 flour 200g of &amp;lsquo;pasta flour&amp;rsquo; (don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what that is) 5 eggs some water Filling
6 large onions 250g fresh ricotta (get the good, dry stuff) ~250g artichoke hearts 2 cloves of garlic a glug of red wine butter tbsp sugar (optional) thyme zest of one lemon some lemon juice some nutmeg some sweet paprika powder seasoning Method Use a standard approach to prepare the pasta dough, see for e.</description></item><item><title>Creamy, Bittersweet, Sharp Pasta</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-10-chicory_gorgonzola/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-10-chicory_gorgonzola/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s just something great about caramelized chicory. While I&amp;rsquo;ve often got there by covering it in honey and balsamic vinegar, I was inclined to look for a similar effect with actual grapes. In additional to the lovely interplay of bitterness and sweetness, there is something light about the acidity of the grapes.
I figured that caramelized onions would only enhance this interplay without distracting too much.
Combining Gorgonzola with pasta water can easily lead to a very creamy cover for the pasta, as can be achieved with other types of cheeses.</description></item><item><title>Markov Random Field Image Denoising</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-27-mrf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-27-mrf/</guid><description>This post describes the application of a Probabilistic Graphical Model for simple image denoising, as suggested in Bishop&amp;rsquo;s chapter 8.3.8. I will attempt to introduce some notions for general context without derivations. Googling will lead to plenty of useful resources. On an introductory level, I enjoyed Daphne Koller&amp;rsquo;s class.
Context: Probabilistic Graphical Models Probabilistic Graphical Models are tools to model and express conditional independencies among a set of random variables.</description></item><item><title>Playlist Chatbot</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-27-playlist-chat-bot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-27-playlist-chat-bot/</guid><description>Countless times have I found myself in the situation of receiving a telegram message of following kind:
On the one hand I find this immensely exciting:
A friend takes time to share something with me. I take pleasure in exploring music per se. Both conjuncted, there is a possibility to bond over music. Hence there is a great amount of potential!
Yet, on the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a mess.</description></item><item><title>Update: Time Is Money</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-26-tim_update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-26-tim_update/</guid><description>A while back, I wrote about Time Is Money.
Back then I ran into several technical problems with modern browsers&amp;rsquo; idle api.
Circumventing these with a somewhat brute approach made it possible to get the extension to run more smoothly. Besides still being able to build it from source, it is now available in the chrome extension store.
Current behaviour In the extension options, a user can specify an hourly wage as well as a set of undesirable websites.</description></item><item><title>Invitations</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-02-invitations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-03-02-invitations/</guid><description>Scenario and goal You are the host of an event for which there are \(n\) candidates to be invited and you possess sufficient resources to host all candidates. Let the nature of the event be such that it seems personally attached to you, yet also fairly polarizing in its experience. In other words:
some invitees will have a desire to decline invitees with a desire to decline will feel bad about declining some non-invitees will have a desire to attend non-invitees with a desire to attend will feel bad about not being able to attend Moreover, one might weigh the ambitions wrt non-desiring invitees and desiring non-invitees differently.</description></item><item><title>Not Buying Tableware</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-23-tableware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 19:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-23-tableware/</guid><description>While mindlessly strolling around the leftover 18th century fortifications of a coastal Moroccan town I came across some streets with vendors of apparently local tableware. I found said tableware to be really beautiful. Sadly, the pure state of admiration only lasted briefly. The latter was soon accompanied and then progressively consumed by the concern of what to buy for whom. It got me quite excited (in a twisted way) and thinking hard about how my own tableware could be complemented, how others could use any tableware.</description></item><item><title>Log, Right?</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-16-log/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 19:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-16-log/</guid><description>Most Machine Learning projects have seen me write a function to log data to a log-file as well as apply a logarithm to a vector. As I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of a conventionally used synonym for the former use of &amp;rsquo;log&amp;rsquo; and the latter is usually referred to as &amp;rsquo;log&amp;rsquo; in mathematics (thereby rejecting the argument I would usually bring up in naming issues: avoid abbreviations and acronyms) a naming problem naturally arises.</description></item><item><title>Capuns</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-25-capuns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-25-capuns/</guid><description>Capuns are dumplings wrapped in chard leaves stemming from the Swiss canton of Graubünden. While they traditionally rely on bacon, I gave sundried tomatoes and mushrooms a shot in the leading role. Umami has to come from somewhere. Moreover I added cheese to the filling and browned with cheese and cream in the oven. I believe both do not necessarily correspond to the default approach.
Ingredients Serves 4 hungry people.</description></item><item><title>2019 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-26-2019_running/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-26-2019_running/</guid><description>As explained in a previous post, I log the distances of my runs. In the following I will make some simple observations based on this data. The data goes back to 2016 and comprises timestamps and running distances in km.
In bad storytelling manner let&amp;rsquo;s start with the most graspable and interesting statistic first: average and overall distance across years. I had never computed those before and had basically no intuition on it at all.</description></item><item><title>Kimchi Pancakes</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-10-03-kimchi-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-10-03-kimchi-pancakes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d argue that those beautifully colored kimchi pancakes are rather on the subtle side when it comes to taste intensity. The kimchi flavor certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t overwhelming. At the same time, leaving it out makes you wish for something.
Ingredients Serves 4 hungry ppl.
Pancake batter 2 eggs 1.5 cups of chopped Kimchi (most likely around 400g) 2 cups of flower 2 cups of corn or potato starch 1.5 cups of kimchi liquid 12 tablespoons of water 1 teaspoon of salt 3 spring onions Dipping sauce some chili flakes a bit of sugar (adjust to taste) Equal parts of:</description></item><item><title>Sort-of-art?</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-09-27-lena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 08:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-09-27-lena/</guid><description>Recently, my friend Theo pointed me towards his amazing idea and execution of programming &amp;lsquo;paintings&amp;rsquo; with the help of randomization.
I was fairly taken by the idea of programming with randomization to create sort-of-art. I kept thinking about cellular automata but reckoned that they often created outcomes that looked:
overly structured in general busy, hard and cold in detail. I figured that the latter could maybe be tackled by applying lots of smoothing, both on input and output image.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Pills: An Intuition</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-09-23-breaking_pills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-09-23-breaking_pills/</guid><description>Motivation Recently, Mark Dominus&amp;rsquo; post on breaking pills appeared on Hacker News. I was surprised to see the author not provide a closed-form and wanted to extend on some of the comments indicating a relation to the harmonic numbers.
Problem Formulation Starting off with a bowl of \(n\) whole pills, you draw from the bowl uniformly at random according to the following mechanism: if the drawn pill is whole, you put back one half of it; if the drawn pill is half, you don&amp;rsquo;t put back anything.</description></item><item><title>Challenge People</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-challenge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-challenge/</guid><description>Abstract This post introduces an arbitrary topic on which I changed my mind, mostly through own reflection. I intend to exemplify my pet theory: I could have changed opinion and landed in a more desirable situation much faster if my original position had been challenged more by my social environment.
An exemplary change of opinion: Messaging Previous position I vividly remember claiming that messaging people one doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk to on a regular basis was pointless, as long as there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very specific topic to discuss, which required a lot of groundwork to be laid out already.</description></item><item><title>Korean Noodle Salad</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-noodles/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a Korean noodle salad. Its raw and at most lukewarm ingredients as well as the the coriander-acidity pairing make it feel light and fresh despite the rich nature of the peanut butter and sesame oil. I can recommend it as a main course on summer evenings.
Preliminaries Bell peppers, carrots and cucumber are meant to be cut in juliennes. The following aspects flow into that decision:</description></item><item><title>Workflow on Leonhard Compute Cluster</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-02-28-leonhard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-02-28-leonhard/</guid><description>Abstract Fortunately, ETH provides many of its students with access to Leonhard, a computer cluster with GPUs. Note that only students with certain coursework or projects are granted access. I have spent and lost a fair amount of time due to poor Google results and will describe a setup for a simple workflow.
Connection In order to ssh to the server, you first need to connect to ETH&amp;rsquo;s VPN.
ssh your_nethz@login.</description></item><item><title>A Beautiful, Derandomized Algorithm</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-01-22-favourite-algorithm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-01-22-favourite-algorithm/</guid><description>Abstract Appreciating the simplicity of powerful randomized algorithms comes easy to me. In the following I will try to describe a naive algorithm relying on a randomized argument. What I find particularly remarkable is that it can easily parry the critique I am so often encountered with when cherishing randomized algorithms: it can trivially be turned deterministic.
MAX-3SAT Is a boolean satisfiability problem. Given a formula in 3-CNF, the goal to satisfy as many clauses as possible.</description></item><item><title>Sklearn Pipelines</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-01-10-sklearn-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 13:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-01-10-sklearn-pipelines/</guid><description>Pipeline of transforms with a final estimator.
Why Whether you&amp;rsquo;re using sklearn transformations already or implementing data wrangling from scratch, there are interesting aspects to squeezing those into an sklearn pipeline. Most notably, this will:
Allow for the usage of sklearn&amp;rsquo;s cross validation. Allow for the usage of sklearn&amp;rsquo;s grid search. Lower the barrier to include sklearn transformations, such as TfidfVectorizer, in the future. It would be possible to do all such processing without a pipeline object: once on the whole dataset.</description></item><item><title>Running Log</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-21-running-log/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-21-running-log/</guid><description>Problem Sports tracking apps offer lots of interesting functionalities regarding the logging of activities. I figured most of what they provided was only interesting in short-term for two reasons.
On the one hand, I changed phones and tracking apps from time to time, which would sometimes lead to a reset of information. Also, some tracking apps were discontinued. You could say they introduced technical debt that I often was not willing or able to carry on.</description></item><item><title>On Advice</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-05-advice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-05-advice/</guid><description>Sometimes concrete advice is fairly context-insensitive: Dale Carnegie suggests to always greet people in the fashion of a dog. Such advice might be useful at times, yet I believe that the upper bound of created value by such concrete yet context-insensitive advice is low.
My impression is that most valuable decisions are context-sensitive by nature, i.e. relying on a lot of individual, complex information. The overwhelming complexity and volume of context can be mistakenly overlooked when formulating advice.</description></item><item><title>On Apologies: A Poor Man's Taxonomy</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-09-09-apologies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-09-09-apologies/</guid><description>I have gotten confused and frustrated over apologies from time to time. They have been a consistent source of miscommunication. I figured that it isn&amp;rsquo;t clear to me what an apology means in the general case. Hence I tried to distinguish possible meanings in more concrete cases.
I &amp;lsquo;regret&amp;rsquo; my action and given the hypothetical chance to undo it, I would. I preferred you not having to bear the negative consequences of my action.</description></item><item><title>Time Is Money</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-29-tim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-29-tim/</guid><description>This post is about a browser add-on that is hopefully a drop in the ocean towards a rather ambitious goal. It&amp;rsquo;s called TimeIsMoney.
Motivation A while back I listened to Sam Harris&amp;rsquo; podcast with Tristan Harris. What remained was following:
I agreed that most technology is agnostic. At the same time, a lot of technology stemming from or being a byproduct of the attention economy is rather geared towards a usage that is a net disadvantage for the user.</description></item><item><title>Matrix Factorization in Collaborative Filtering</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-10-cf-mf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-10-cf-mf/</guid><description>The Task We are given a set of tuples representing user-movie ratings, \(\mathcal{R} = \{(i,j,r)\}\), where \(i\) is the user index, \(j\) is the movie index and \(r \in [0, \dots, 5]\) the rating. In the most common scenarios, only a fraction of all user-movie pairs are rated, hence we can talk about sparse data. In other words, most users have only rated a few movies. Now we want to obtain sensible predictions for movies a user has not rated.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Kevin. I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer Scientist. You can find me on Twitter and GitHub.
I enjoy attempting to derive from first principles &amp;ndash; in math, programming or in real life&amp;rsquo;s decision making. Professionally, I do work in Data Engineering, Data Science, Machine Learning Engineering, Software Engineering and Quantitative Analysis.
On this website I try to share my views in order to force myself to condense and distill thoughts and ideas freely floating around in my mind.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/projects/</guid><description>Work I am fortunate enough that some of the work done at QuantCo is open source.
Datajudge Datajudge is a Python data testing library. Datajudge allows for the convenient expression and testing of expectations between different data source in database. It integrates nicely with pytest. For more, read our blog post or have a look at an example in the documentation.
Pytsql pytsql is a Python library enabling the execution and parametrization of raw mssql scripts.</description></item></channel></rss>