<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on Blog</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Kevin Klein</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 07:38:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevinkle.in/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use It Or Lose It</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2023-05-30-use_it_or_lose_it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2023-05-30-use_it_or_lose_it/</guid><description>I long held the belief that knowing things (by heart)1 was both overrated and not too important. Rather, I thought that being able to quickly access and digest information was the only thing that mattered. I still think that the latter is incredibly important, but I changed my mind on the former.
Why remember? Tl;dr: I now think that knowing things matters to some extent and would like to memorize.</description></item><item><title>How Much Is a Hundred Bucks?</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2023-04-23-100_dollars_worth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2023-04-23-100_dollars_worth/</guid><description>The not so mobile-friendly calculator accompanying this post can be found here.
The value of time, the value of money There are various ways of trying to assess the value of something. For instance, one might define the value of a resource by how much someone else is willing to pay for it. In the domain of time, we could ask the question of the hourly rate someone is willing to pay for our time/labor and consider that the value of our time.</description></item><item><title>2022 in Exercise</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-27-2022_running/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 02:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-27-2022_running/</guid><description>As another year is coming to an end I&amp;rsquo;m curious: What does the exercise data have to tell me? I did something similar in 2021, 2020 as well as in 2019.
2019 2020 2021 2022 running distance [km] 962 1295 1403 1150 #runs 107 123 127 127 share of running among exercise activities 79.26% 58.57% 54.27% 38.89% cycling distance [km] 1044 660 1340 #bike rides 20 18 36 #strength trainings 6 63 82 110 #exercise activities 135 210 234 324 #different kinds of exercise activities 6 11 17 I figure I have completed my metamorphosis from a hobby runner to an aspirational jack of all traits, master of none.</description></item><item><title>2022 in Consuming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-22-2022_consuming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-22-2022_consuming/</guid><description>Just rambling about some books and music I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to in 2022. I did a similar thing in 2021 and 2020.
Books What I Talk About When I Talk About Running - Haruki Murakami I&amp;rsquo;m reading this constantly wondering why I&amp;rsquo;m reading it but never contemplating stopping.
Faserland - Christian Kracht The nonchalant absurdity sometimes reminded me of Jack Kerouac. So many things I couldn&amp;rsquo;t relate to and so many questions I&amp;rsquo;d need to ask about.</description></item><item><title>Status Symbols</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-21-status_symbols/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-12-21-status_symbols/</guid><description>What is a status symbol?
While the Cambridge dictionary restricts status symbols to possessions, wikipedia takes a more permissive stance and defines them as
a visible, external symbol of one&amp;rsquo;s social position, an indicator of economic or social status
I&amp;rsquo;ll side with the latter. This, of course, bears the questions of what social status actually is, which I will, of course, eschew.
Rather, a list of indicators I believe to have perceived with regards to social status:</description></item><item><title>Mantras</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-05-mantras/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-09-05-mantras/</guid><description>A system just can&amp;rsquo;t respond to short-term changes when it has long-term delays. Donella H. Meadows, Thinking in Systems Always be closing. Am meisten erreicht man, wann man den Lustgewinn aus den Quellen psyschicher und intellektueller Arbeit genügend zu erhöhen versteht. Sigmund Freud, Das Unbehagen in der Kultur Be a parent to yourself. A wise Hacker News user Defend those who are absent. Steven Covey, 7 Habbits of Highly Effective People Don&amp;rsquo;t confuse effort with result.</description></item><item><title>Observations About My Gym</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-25-gym/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 07:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-06-25-gym/</guid><description>The gym operators have three folders in their open office, one of which is titled &amp;lsquo;problems&amp;rsquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;m gently reminded that I haven&amp;rsquo;t leetcoded in a long while and that the days taking classes on algorithms and data structures have long been gone while trying to find a pair of matching dumbbells of a specific weight.
A guy once seriously protested that he cannot possibly not be topless while training.
You have to pay extra to take a shower.</description></item><item><title>Goals Are Arbitrary</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-18-goals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-02-18-goals/</guid><description>I have the pleasure of having impressive friends who have completed and continue to complete spectacular athletic feats. Some crossed the alps with a single speed steel tandem bike. Some run 10k in 35&amp;rsquo;. Some run half-marathons with more than 2000m of elevation literally called inferno. And then, of course, there is the camp of people who go about this whole ironman business.
Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a difficult relation to &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>2021 in Consuming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-28-2021_consuming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-28-2021_consuming/</guid><description>Just rambling about some books, music and podcasts I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to in 2021. I did a similar thing in 2020.
Books A Supposedly Fun Thing I&amp;rsquo;ll Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments - David Foster Wallace I much preferred the short story about the dynamics of professional tennis over DFW&amp;rsquo;s hesitant adventures on the high seas after which the book is titled. The distinguishing quality might have been positivity. While tries to convey a lot of criticism and scepticism towards tennis, yet can&amp;rsquo;t help but let raw rays of juvenile sunshine through his cover of rationality.</description></item><item><title>2021 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-27-2021_running/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 02:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-12-27-2021_running/</guid><description>As another year is coming to an end I&amp;rsquo;m curious: What has my running looked like this year? I did something similar in 2020 as well as in 2019.
The gist of it 2018 2019 2020 2021 distance [km] 430 962 1295 1381 avg distance [km] 6.61 9.08 10.53 11.05 #runs 65 107 123 124 #sports activities 81 135 210 231 share of running among sports activities 80.25% 79.26% 58.57% 53.</description></item><item><title>Expectations are Twofold</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-17-expecations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-17-expecations/</guid><description>I caught myself making the mistake of thinking I wasn&amp;rsquo;t holding expectations when in fact, I was.
When telling myself to not have a certain expectation against someone, I did usually make sure to control my behaviour towards them. If I anticipated that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the expectation of an event taking place, I made sure not to make the responsible person feel negatively about the non-event. I figured that not holding the expectation would mean that I may not act upset or angry towards them.</description></item><item><title>I Could Care Less</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-13-caring/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 18:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-13-caring/</guid><description>While I think that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing okay when it comes to not caring too much about other people&amp;rsquo;s perception of me, I believe to have spotted some weak spots recently.
I think there is still a distinction to be made when it comes to &amp;lsquo;caring&amp;rsquo;. I feel like there is a qualitative difference between caring about what exactly others think of me when in their presence and caring about an imagine I have of myself - hypothetically representing me towards others - but practically never witnessed by anyone.</description></item><item><title>2020 in Consuming</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-02-2020_consuming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-01-02-2020_consuming/</guid><description>Just rambling about some books, podcasts and records I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to a bunch over 2020.
Books How to Solve It - George Pólya Classical asymmetry: obvious once you see it.
Slaughterhouse Five - Kurt Vonnegut I think I&amp;rsquo;ll remember the poor soul claiming to have lived through much worse until he didn&amp;rsquo;t.
Consider the Lobster - David Foster Wallace This was when I realized how bad at languages I am.</description></item><item><title>2020 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-12-27-2020_running/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-12-27-2020_running/</guid><description>Yet another year&amp;rsquo;s almost over. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at my year 2020 in running, just as I did in 2019.
Yearly comparison 2018 2019 2020 distance [km] 430 962 1295 avg distance [km] 6.61 9.08 10.53 number of runs 65 107 123 share of running among sport activities 80.25% 79.26% 58.57% I picked up going to the gym in late 2019 and started cycling every now and then in 2020, hence the lower share of running.</description></item><item><title>The Value of the Past</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-25-value-of-past/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 15:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-10-25-value-of-past/</guid><description>When looking into the future, the definition of ambitions is often intertwined with an assessment of their feasibility. There are two, frequently opposing, guiding principles at work:
Be who, how and what you want to be. The past tells you what works for you and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t. The former being a fairly idealistic and empowering maxim, possibly reminiscent of rationalism, I like to think of the latter as Realpolitik on a personal level with a scent of empiricism.</description></item><item><title>Not Buying Tableware</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-23-tableware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 19:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-01-23-tableware/</guid><description>While mindlessly strolling around the leftover 18th century fortifications of a coastal Moroccan town I came across some streets with vendors of apparently local tableware. I found said tableware to be really beautiful. Sadly, the pure state of admiration only lasted briefly. The latter was soon accompanied and then progressively consumed by the concern of what to buy for whom. It got me quite excited (in a twisted way) and thinking hard about how my own tableware could be complemented, how others could use any tableware.</description></item><item><title>2019 in Running</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-26-2019_running/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-26-2019_running/</guid><description>As explained in a previous post, I log the distances of my runs. In the following I will make some simple observations based on this data. The data goes back to 2016 and comprises timestamps and running distances in km.
In bad storytelling manner let&amp;rsquo;s start with the most graspable and interesting statistic first: average and overall distance across years. I had never computed those before and had basically no intuition on it at all.</description></item><item><title>Challenge People</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-challenge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-challenge/</guid><description>Abstract This post introduces an arbitrary topic on which I changed my mind, mostly through own reflection. I intend to exemplify my pet theory: I could have changed opinion and landed in a more desirable situation much faster if my original position had been challenged more by my social environment.
An exemplary change of opinion: Messaging Previous position I vividly remember claiming that messaging people one doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk to on a regular basis was pointless, as long as there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a very specific topic to discuss, which required a lot of groundwork to be laid out already.</description></item><item><title>On Advice</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-05-advice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-10-05-advice/</guid><description>Sometimes concrete advice is fairly context-insensitive: Dale Carnegie suggests to always greet people in the fashion of a dog. Such advice might be useful at times, yet I believe that the upper bound of created value by such concrete yet context-insensitive advice is low.
My impression is that most valuable decisions are context-sensitive by nature, i.e. relying on a lot of individual, complex information. The overwhelming complexity and volume of context can be mistakenly overlooked when formulating advice.</description></item><item><title>On Apologies: A Poor Man's Taxonomy</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-09-09-apologies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-09-09-apologies/</guid><description>I have gotten confused and frustrated over apologies from time to time. They have been a consistent source of miscommunication. I figured that it isn&amp;rsquo;t clear to me what an apology means in the general case. Hence I tried to distinguish possible meanings in more concrete cases.
I &amp;lsquo;regret&amp;rsquo; my action and given the hypothetical chance to undo it, I would. I preferred you not having to bear the negative consequences of my action.</description></item><item><title>Time Is Money</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-29-tim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 16:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2018-07-29-tim/</guid><description>This post is about a browser add-on that is hopefully a drop in the ocean towards a rather ambitious goal. It&amp;rsquo;s called TimeIsMoney.
Motivation A while back I listened to Sam Harris&amp;rsquo; podcast with Tristan Harris. What remained was following:
I agreed that most technology is agnostic. At the same time, a lot of technology stemming from or being a byproduct of the attention economy is rather geared towards a usage that is a net disadvantage for the user.</description></item></channel></rss>