<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipe on Blog</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/tags/recipe/</link><description>Recent content in recipe on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Kevin Klein</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevinkle.in/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PB Granola</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-20-pb_granola/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-05-20-pb_granola/</guid><description>Ingredients 300g of rolled oats 100g of dark chocolate 100g of pecan nuts 50g of Brazil nuts 3 massively heaped tablespoons of crunchy peanut butter 2 massively heaped tablespoons of coconut oil 3 tablespoons of honey (preferably runny) 2 tablespoons of cocoa powder 1 tablespoon of vanilla sugar 1 tablespoon of cinnamon a dash of salt Method Roughly chop the nuts and finely chop the chocolate. Mix all together, making sure the coconut oil melts in the process of doing so.</description></item><item><title>Fig Appetizers</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-01-fig_appetizers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2022-01-01-fig_appetizers/</guid><description>Quick to make, satisfying to eat.
Ingredients Puff pastry Figs (preferably fresh ones; if not, dried ones are ok, too) Ricotta Rocket Method Cut some parts of the puff pastry. I figure both rectangles and squares should work. While all sizes &amp;lsquo;go&amp;rsquo;, I think that in principle one wants to use as little dough per fixed filling size as possible. In the same vein, I would try to make the pastry as thin as possible.</description></item><item><title>Automn Pie</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-10-17-pie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 10:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-10-17-pie/</guid><description>This is a really hearty dish. I&amp;rsquo;d claim that the filling of the pie can easily be prepared in advance.
Core ingredients Serves 4 okay-ish hungry people.
1kg smoked tofu 1kg green beans 500 ml coconut milk ~500g shortcrust dough 2 cans of chickpeas 3 carrots 3 large yellow onions 3 gloves of garlic half a thumb of ginger small chili soy sauce black bean sauce tomato purée soy sauce red wine 1 egg Method Strain your chickpeas and separate them out on a baking tray.</description></item><item><title>Flaky Tofu</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-09-25-flaky-tofu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 10:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2021-09-25-flaky-tofu/</guid><description>Ingredients Serves 3 hungry fellows.
Tofu 1kg firm tofu 200 mL unsweeetened soy milk 100 g flour 3 tablespoons[0]corn starch 200g unsweetened corn flakes Dipping sauce 4 tablespoons peanut paste 4 tablespoons black bean sauce (see below for an image) 4 tablespoons tomato purée 2 tablespoons of rice wine vinegar dash of soy sauce soymilk corn starch Salad ~500g carrots 2 large cucumbers sesame oil soy sauce rice wine vinegar Method Get ahold of two shallow dishes for the batter.</description></item><item><title>Fig Quiche</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-07-25-fig_quiche/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-07-25-fig_quiche/</guid><description>Ingredients 300g shortcrust dough large bunch of basil ~200g Soft, creamy goat cheese, e.g. Chavroux ~400g of figs (both fresh and dried are ok) 4-6 red onions 2 cloves of garlic zest of one lemon ~3 eggs ~80ml cream [0] some lemon juice some nutmeg some sweet paprika powder seasoning Method Slice the red onions in rings and fry them under medium-high heat with both olive oil and butter.</description></item><item><title>Orange Pink Eggs</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-16-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 21:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-16-eggs/</guid><description>I have a feeling that hard-boiled eggs are conventially viewed as unsexy. In spite of that, I gave pickling them a shot.
Ingredients 8 eggs 1 cup of white balsamic vinegar 1/2 cup of liquid from tinned beets 2 tbsp cardamon pods 2 tbsp cumin seeds 2 tbsp coriander seeds 2 tbsp pepper corns 1 tbsp fennel seeds 1 tbsp mustard seeds a few cloves a few bay leaves 2 cloves of garlic 2 tbsp curry powder 2 tbsp turmeric 2 tbsp sweet paprika powder 2 tbsp salt 3 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp garam masala Method Boil the eggs as little as possible while making sure they&amp;rsquo;re actually boiled.</description></item><item><title>Creamy, Bittersweet, Sharp Pasta</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-10-chicory_gorgonzola/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:38:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2020-05-10-chicory_gorgonzola/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s just something great about caramelized chicory. While I&amp;rsquo;ve often got there by covering it in honey and balsamic vinegar, I was inclined to look for a similar effect with actual grapes. In additional to the lovely interplay of bitterness and sweetness, there is something light about the acidity of the grapes.
I figured that caramelized onions would only enhance this interplay without distracting too much.
Combining Gorgonzola with pasta water can easily lead to a very creamy cover for the pasta, as can be achieved with other types of cheeses.</description></item><item><title>Capuns</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-25-capuns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-12-25-capuns/</guid><description>Capuns are dumplings wrapped in chard leaves stemming from the Swiss canton of Graubünden. While they traditionally rely on bacon, I gave sundried tomatoes and mushrooms a shot in the leading role. Umami has to come from somewhere. Moreover I added cheese to the filling and browned with cheese and cream in the oven. I believe both do not necessarily correspond to the default approach.
Ingredients Serves 4 hungry people.</description></item><item><title>Kimchi Pancakes</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-10-03-kimchi-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-10-03-kimchi-pancakes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d argue that those beautifully colored kimchi pancakes are rather on the subtle side when it comes to taste intensity. The kimchi flavor certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t overwhelming. At the same time, leaving it out makes you wish for something.
Ingredients Serves 4 hungry ppl.
Pancake batter 2 eggs 1.5 cups of chopped Kimchi (most likely around 400g) 2 cups of flower 2 cups of corn or potato starch 1.5 cups of kimchi liquid 12 tablespoons of water 1 teaspoon of salt 3 spring onions Dipping sauce some chili flakes a bit of sugar (adjust to taste) Equal parts of:</description></item><item><title>Korean Noodle Salad</title><link>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://kevinkle.in/posts/2019-08-10-noodles/</guid><description>This is a recipe for a Korean noodle salad. Its raw and at most lukewarm ingredients as well as the the coriander-acidity pairing make it feel light and fresh despite the rich nature of the peanut butter and sesame oil. I can recommend it as a main course on summer evenings.
Preliminaries Bell peppers, carrots and cucumber are meant to be cut in juliennes. The following aspects flow into that decision:</description></item></channel></rss>